## CHARLIE BROOKE O'HARA

San Diego, CA

805.403.3066 charlie.b.ohara@gmail.com www.charliebohara.com

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

PYTHON PYTEST

**JAVA** 

SPARK HADOOP PIG

SQL

LINUX CLI BASH SCRIPTING

DOCKER

RUBY RUBY ON RAILS RSPEC

HTML CSS JAVASCRIPT

GIT

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Data engineer experienced with writing Python scripts for automation, working with AWS infrastructure, and building Hadoop MapReduce, Spark SQL, and PySpark applications. Quick to learn new technologies and capable of creating functional applications with little guidance. Always ready jump in and help the team, and consistently provides stellar service to stakeholders. Earned a 92% on the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam, proving a strong ability to absorb and retain information.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Operations Engineer, Verve**

San Diego, CA — July 2017 - present

- Build Hadoop MapReduce applications that automatically process new AWS S3 or SQS input in order to build critical datasets that are published to appropriate downstream consumers
- Write Python scripts to automate operational processes to streamline delivery
- Work with a team to establish a workflow for building, distributing, and ultimately executing against code artifacts within our ecosystem

#### Big Data Engineer, Algebraix Data

San Diego, CA — February 2017 - July 2017

- Built and ran Spark SQL and PySpark applications in AWS EMR to test proprietary query acceleration algorithm against TPC-H and TPC-DS benchmarks
- Wrote bash scripts to streamline product installation in a variety of environments
- Wrote Python scripts for general automation and log analysis

### **Quality Assurance Engineer, Grizzly**

San Diego, CA — September 2016 - February 2017

- Setup and built client Wordpress applications while leveraging Docker
- Wrote PHPUnit tests and configured continuous integration tool Wercker
- Wrote Python scripts for data mining, cleaning, analysis, and transfer

#### Junior Software Engineer Apprenticeship, The Firehose Project

Remote — March 2016 - August 2016

- Worked with a remote team to build a Ruby on Rails chess web application following agile methodologies with pair programming collaboration
- Built complex business logic for chess piece movements thorough test-driven development using RSpec
- Leverage jQuery User Interface and AJAX to move pieces in the browser and Pusher websocket for communication between players

#### **EDUCATION**

University of California, Santa Barbara

Bachelor's - Biology

Santa Barbara City College

Associate's - Engineering

City College of San Francisco

Associate's - Computer Science